Records of the Athletics Department RG.41
New York University Archives
- RG 41.1: Basketball, 1906-1997
  - Basketball Brochure and Schedule, 1962-1963 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Basketball Brochure and Schedule, 1963-1964 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Basketball Brochure and Schedule, 1964-1965 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Basketball Press Guide, 1965-1966 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Basketball Programs and Schedule, 1966-1967 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Basketball Programs and Schedule, 1967-1968 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Basketball Programs and Schedules, 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Basketball Programs and Schedule, 1969-1970 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Basketball Program, 1970-1971 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Basketball Events Announcement, 1983-1984 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Basketball Programs and Schedules, 1982-1983 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Basketball Programs, 1983-1984 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Basketball Programs and Schedules, 1984-1985 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Basketball Programs and Schedules, 1985-1986 (Box 16a, Folder 1)
  - Basketball Events and Tickets, 1986-1987 (Box 16a, Folder 2)
  - Basketball Programs and Schedules, 1987-1988 (Box 16a, Folder 3)
  - Basketball Program and Schedule, 1988-1989 (Box 16a, Folder 4)
  - Basketball Programs and Schedules, 1989-1990 (Box 16a, Folder 5)
  - Basketball Programs, 1990-1991 (Box 16a, Folder 6)
  - Basketball Programs and Tickets, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Basketball Programs, Events, and Tickets, 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Basketball Programs and Tickets, 1993-1994 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Basketball Programs, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Basketball Programs, Nov.-Dec. 1993 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Basketball Programs (2 folders), 1994 (Box 17, Folder 6-7)
  - Men and Women's Basketball, 1994-1995 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Men and Women's Basketball, 1995-1996 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Men and Women's Basketball, 1996-1997 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Men and Women's Basketball, 1997-1999, 2016 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Basketball Biography: Alcindor, Lew, 1965-1966 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Abba, Chuck, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Alexander, Bruce, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Anderson, Larry, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Barden, Al, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Becker, Abe, 1951 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Bennett, Ray, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Blaha, Don, 1960-1963 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Boose, Tom, 1960-1961 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Brasco, Jim, 1951 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Brown, Richard, 1962-1964 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Bucek, John, 1958 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Carnevale, Ben, 1960-1970 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Chappell, Andrew, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Clarke, Frederick, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Costigan, Pat, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Coward, Jim, 1940-1950 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Cunningham, Russ, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Deehan, Bill, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Deluca, Tom, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Dinapoli, Mike, 1958 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Dobleman, Paul, 1967-1970 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Dyer, Richard, 1962-1966 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Eplan, Ray, 1958 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Felton, Duane, 1966-1967 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Ferkauf, Sid, 1947-1948 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Filardi, Al, 1960-1962 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Fisch, Gene, 1961-1964 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Forman, Donald, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Geschwer, Mark, 1966-1970 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Galliard, Clem, 1961-1965 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Frontera, Jim, 1961-1963 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Groothuis, Mark, 1962-1963 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Guma, Rory, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Hairston, Harold, 1962-1965 (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Henderson, Brooks, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Jensen, Bill, 1950 (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Jordan, Steve, 1961-1963 (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - Kaplan, Bruce, 1963-1967 (Box 18, Folder 39)
  - Keith, Rit, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 40)
  - Klein, Irwin (King-Kong), 1963-1970 (Box 18, Folder 41)
  - Kramer, Barry, 1960-1970 (Box 18, Folder 42)
  - Lam. Ken, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Lancaster, Jim, 1961 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Loche, Art, 1960-1965 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Lumpp, Ray, 1954-1959 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Lyon, Sam, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - McKenzie, Stanley, 1962-1966 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Maloney, Donald E., 1965 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Mangiapane, Frank, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Miller, James, 1964-1968 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Muzio, Michael R., 1964-1969 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Nachamkin, Boris, 1951-1962 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Naimoli, Ralph, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Nidds, Jimmy, 1952-1953 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - O'Connor, John J., 1947-1950 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - O'Neil, Jack, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - O'Neil, Neil, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Paprocky, Ray, 1959-1962 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Patton, Bob, 1960-1967 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Porrata, Dolf, 1966-1970 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Ramsey, Cal, 1956-1961 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Reiner, Mark, 1960-1962 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Rohan, Jack, 1958-1967 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Rooks, Carlton, 1963-1964 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Rubenstein, Willie, 1956-1967 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Sanders, Tom, 1958-1966 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Schayes, Dolph, 1948-1970 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Schwartz, Bob, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Seeman, Mel, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Signorile, James, 1967-1971 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Simmons, John, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Skedzielewski, Jim, 1969-1970 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Smith, Edward, 1932-1936 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Stefkovich, Steve, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Tanenbaum, Sid, 1943-1986 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Turpin, Frank, 1960-1961 (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Vaughn, Jay, 1970-1971 (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - White, Martin J., 1964-1965 (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Williams, Robert A., 1962-1969 (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Young, Harvey, 1969 (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - All Time Basketball Results, 1906-1981 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Basketball Alumni, 1906-1940 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Alumni Basketball Recruiting Committee, June 1968 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - All-America Selections, 1963-1968 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Comments About Former NYU Basketball Players, 1971-1972 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Mike Muzio Coach Notebook, 1980-1981 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Balanced Basketball League, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Basketball Writers Association, 1965-1969 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Clinics, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Georgetown "Incident", 1966 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Basketball Hall of Fame, 1960-1968 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Madison Square Garden, 1953-1969 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Basketball Misc., 1925-1970 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - NCAA All-Time Records, 1943-1962 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - NCAA Misc., 1943-1962 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Notre Dame Series, 1934-1968 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Varsity Alumni Basketball, 1968-1971 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - 1919-1920 Basketball, 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Freshman Basketball 1930-1931, 1939-1940, 1930-1940 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - "It's a Game Guy's Game" -Howard Cann, Undated (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - NYU Women's Basketball National Champions pennant, 1997 (Box 236)
- RG 41.2: Baseball, 1899-1972
  History of Baseball at NYU
  NYU's baseball program was established in the 1870s as something akin to a club sport. The move to the University Heights campus in 1894, with its expansive athletic facilities and fields, allowed the NYU baseball team to become a legitimate intercollegiate competitor. The team was not very successful in its early years, however, with the varsity team losing all but one of 13 games in 1902.
  The team did experience a resurgence in the 1920s under coach William McCarthy. Between 1922 and 1961, he led the NYU Violets to 476 victories and 258 losses. Among the outstanding players of the 1920s was George "Kiddo" Davis, the first NYU baseball starter to break into the major leagues. In 1927, Davis signed with the New York Yankees, and six years later the Yankees won the World Series. Numerous other baseball alumni would go on to play in the major leagues. By the early 1970s the University's financial situation was critical, and radical changes to the overall budget were necessary. The University Heights campus was sold, and the baseball team was cut. With the loss of the Bronx campus there was no space to practice or play home games. Baseball was reinstated in 1996 as a club sport. It joined the NCBA and played in Division II, District II alongside Hofstra University, Cabrini College, and Rider University.
  Varsity baseball returned to NYU in spring 2015 as a Division III sport when NYU-Poly, which had its own team, officially became part of NYU.
  Series 2 includes early baseball tickets, schedules, and programs, as well as a scrapbook created for the 1902 baseball season. Beginning in 1941 and continuing until 1972 there are folders organized by year with an assortment of baseball schedules, player and team statistics, newspaper clippings, and NYU press releases. There are also a number of player biographies.
  - Baseball Ticket 1899, 1899 3 June (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - NYU Baseball Schedule, 1902 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Baseball Scrapbook, 1902-1903 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Baseball Schedule, 1928 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Baseball Schedule, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Baseball Schedule, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Baseball Schedule, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Baseball Schedule, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Baseball Game Scores, 1872-1963 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Baseball Game Scores, 1873-1937 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Pre-1940 Baseball Information, 1922-1940 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, & Press Releases, 1941 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, & Press Releases, 1942 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, & Press Releases, 1943 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, & Press Releases, 1944 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, & Press Releases, 1945 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, & Press Releases, 1946 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, & Press Releases, 1947 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, & Press Releases, 1948 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, & Press Releases, 1949 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, & Press Releases, 1950 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, & Press Releases, 1951 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, & Press Releases, 1952 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, & Press Releases, 1953 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, & Press Releases, 1954 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, & Press Releases, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, & Press Releases, 1956 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, & Press Releases, 1957 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, & Press Releases, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, & Press Releases, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, & Press Releases, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, & Press Releases, 1961 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, & Press Releases, 1962 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, Articles, & Press Releases, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, Articles, & Press Releases, 1964 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, Articles, & Press Releases, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, Articles, & Press Releases, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, Articles, & Press Releases, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, Articles, & Press Releases, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Baseball Clippings, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Baseball Schedule & Press Release, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Baseball Caption, 1968 9 May (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Baseball Players, 1968 27 June (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Baseball Facts, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Baseball Team Articles & Press Releases, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Blank Scorecards, 1965-1966 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, Articles, & Press Releases, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Atlantic College Summer Baseball League, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Baseball Clippings, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Baseball Luncheon, 1969 22 May (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Cardasis Memo, 1969 3 June (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - St. Johns vs. NYU, 1969 3 April (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - NYU vs. Temple, 1969 10 May (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Baseball Notes, 1969 23 May (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - NYU at NCAA, 1969 4 June (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Collegiate Baseball Newspaper, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - National Collegiate Baseball Writers Association, 1968-1969 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Baseball Team Schedules, Statistics, Articles, & Press Releases, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Baseball Team Statistics, Articles, & Press Releases, 1971 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Baseball Team Statistics, Articles, & Press Releases, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Baseball Notebooks, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Baseball Clippings, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Collegiate Baseball, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - NYU vs. University of Pennsylvania, 1970 8 April (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - NYU vs. St. John, 1970 13 April (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - NYU vs. Wagner, 1970 1 May (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - NYU vs. Fordham, 1970 25 April (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Baseball Opener, 1970 25 March (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Kalish Profile, 1970 21 April (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Collins Feature, 1970 1 May (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Marino Feature, 1970 13 May (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Baseball Finals, 1970 25 May (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Baseball Round-Up, 1970 25 May (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Baseball Uniform Orders, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Berliner, David, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Branca, Ralph, 1957-1964 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Brown, Arthur, 1967-1968 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Buchita, Al, 1965-1967 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Cardasis, James, 1968-1969 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Casey, Tom, 1950 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Castiglione, Bob, 1965-1967 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Currado, John, 1971-1972 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Davis, George "Kiddo", 1936 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Geraciotti, Lawrence, 1961-1970 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Lasker, Gary, 1962-1963 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Mele, Sam, 1961-1967 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Milinis, Bill, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Newberry, Don, 1962-1964 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Novick, Don, 1964-1965 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Payerle, Charles, 1952 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Ray, Steve, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Silverstein, Sanford, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Yost, Eddie, 1961-1969 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - NYU Baseball Uniform - Jersey, undated (Box 229)
- RG 41.3: Fencing, 1925-1995
  History of Fencing at NYU
  Fencing became a varsity sport in 1923. The NYU fencing team has attracted talented athletes and has regularly sent students and alumni to compete in the Olympics. From the late 1950s to the 1970s the men's fencing team was one of the best in the nation, earning 12 national titles between 1947 and 1976. The women's team has also been very successful, winning national championships 10 times. Both teams continue to compete in NCAA Division I. Twenty-eight NYU fencers competed at the Olympics between 1928-1984. Of these 28, one competed for Finland, one for Italy, and the rest for the United States.
  Men's fencing results for 1927-2014 can be found in Archives H. Women's fencing results for 1928-2014 can be found in Archives H.
  Series 3 is comprised of materials generated between 1925 and 1995 related to fencing team activities at New York University. Papers include fencing team schedules, press releases concerning players and the teams, team rosters, game and championship programs, as well as player biographies.
  - Fencing All-Time Records, 1927-1962 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Fencing National Championships, 1959-1972 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Fencing Team Schedules, Press Releases, & Clippings, 1925-1940 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Fencing Team Schedules, Press Releases, & Clippings, 1940-1947 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Fencing Team Rosters & Schedules, 1947-1950 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Fencing Alumni Roster, 1950 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Fencing Team Rosters, 1950-1955 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Fencing NCAA Championships, 1956, 1959-1972 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Fencing Team Schedules & Rosters, 1955-1956 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Fencing Team Rosters, Programs, & Schedules, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Interscholastic Schoolboy Fencing Tournament, 1952-1962 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Olympic and Pan-American Games, 1957, 1958, 1960, 1962 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Fencing Team Rosters & Schedules, 1957-1958 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Women's Fencing Team Schedules & Correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Fencing Team Schedules, Rosters, & Press Releases, 1958-1959 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Fencing Team Rosters, Press Releases, & Schedules, 1959-1960 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Fencing Team Rosters, Press Releases, & Clippings, 1960-1961 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Fencing Team Rosters, Clippings, & Programs, 1961-1962 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Fencing Team Rosters, Clippings, Schedules, & Press Releases, 1962-1963 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Varsity Fencing Team, 1946-1947 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Women's Fencing, 1946-1947 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Fencing Team Clippings, Rosters, & Press Releases, 1963-1964 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Fencing Team Rosters, Schedules, Clippings, & Press Releases, 1964-1965 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Fencing Team Rosters, Clippings, & Press Releases, 1965-1966 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Intercollegiate Fencing Association Championships, 1969-1973 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Intercollegiate Fencing Association Championships, 1956, 1959-1967 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Fencing Team Rosters, Clippings, Press Releases, 1966-1967 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Fencing Team Schedules, Clippings, Rosters, & Press Releases, 1967-1968 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Women's Fencing Season, 1967-1968 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Fencing Team Rosters, Schedules, Clippings, & Press Releases, 1968-1969 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - 72nd Intercollegiate Fencing Association Championships at NYU, 1969 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Intercollegiate Fencing Association Championships, 1952, 1967, 1969, 1970, 1971, 1972, 1978, 1980 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Interscholastic (Schoolboy) Fencing Tournament, 1963-1968 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Women's Season Papers, 1963-1964 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Intercollegiate Women's Fencing Association Championship Material, 1964-1968 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Women's Fencing Records, Rosters, and Materials, 1964-1966 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Women's Fencing Materials, 1966-1968 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Women's Fencing Rosters, Schedules, and Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Fencing Team Rosters, Press Releases, and Schedules, 1969-1970 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Fencing Team Rosters, Schedules, Clippings, and Press Releases, 1970-1971 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Interscholastic (Schoolboy) Fencing Tournament, 1964-1970 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Sally Pechinsky Interview, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Women's Fencing Team Rosters, Schedules, Clippings, and Press Releases, 1969-1970 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Walter Krause - Outstanding Athlete Press Release, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Fencing Captain Wayne Krause Press Release, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Amateur Fencers League of America - Fencing Rules and Manual, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Fencing Coach Csajaghy Retires, 1970 15 July (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Fencing Prospects, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Sebastiani to Coach, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Intercollegiate Fencing Association Championship, 1970 5 March (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Women's Fencing Team Clippings, Rosters, Schedules, and Press Releases, 1970-1973 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Fencing Team Schedules, Press Releases, Clippings, and Rosters, 1971-1972 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Fencing Team Schedules, Pamphlets, Clippings, and Press Releases, 1971-1972 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Intercollegiate Women's Fencing Association Material, 1952-1978 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - IWFA Championship at NYU, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Women's and Men's Fencing Season Materials, 1972-1973 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Women's Fencing Team Schedules, Rosters, Score Cards, and Rankings, 1973-1974 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Intercollegiate Fencing Association Championship, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Women's Fencing Team Materials, 1974-1976 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Women's Fencing Press Release, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Fencing Team Programs, 1985-1986 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Fencing Programs and a Championship Ribbon, 1994-1995 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Abby, Carol, 1965-1966 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Apostol, Paul, 1966-1972 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Castello, James M., 1946-1966 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Castello, Julio M., 1935-1969 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Csajaghy, Bela, 1968 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Dasaro, Mike, 1958-1964 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Davis, Albert E., 1965-1966 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - DeCapriles, Jose R., 1969 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - DeCapriles, Miguel, 1952-1967 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Gaylor, Michael, 1967-1968 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Jones, Julia, Undated (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Masin, George, 1966-1968 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - McGlennon, Harriet, 1941 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Menendez, Ableardo, Undated (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Peredo, Al, 1961-1964 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Sebastiani, Michel, Undated (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - William, Thomas, 1952 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Wallner, Herman, 1952 (Box 31, Folder 18)
- RG 41.4: Football, 1889-1967
  History of Football at NYU
  The NYU football team was founded in 1873. It was one of the first university-sponsored teams in the U.S., preceded only by Princeton, Rutgers, and Yale. During its inaugural season, NYU lost its only game, to the Stevens Institute of Technology, which was also a brand new team.
  Few documents from NYU football's early years have survived, but existing records indicate few wins early on. Following the acquisition of the University Heights campus in 1894, the team began playing and practicing on Ohio Field.
  NYU was integral to the regulation of college athletics in the early 20th century, helping to found the Intercollegiate Athletic Association of the United States, precursor to the National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA).
  The late 1920s became known as the "Golden Era" of NYU football. The school played a number of games at the new Yankee Stadium, and coach John Meehan led the team to 49 wins and only 15 losses. When Meehan left in 1931, the team was unable to continue its earlier successes, in part because World War II drained the player pool and financial resources.
  After the war, the team tried to recapture its previous popularity and success, but increased funds did not lead to increasing interest or ticket sales. In 1953 the team was disbanded. Football made a short return in 1964 as a club sport but never caught on and was officially discontinued in 1967 because of lack of interest.
  This series contains a number of player biographies, including newspaper clippings and NYU press information on specific players, team rosters and schedules, statistics, game programs, and NYU press releases concerning the team. These materials range in date from 1889 until 1967.
  - Football Hall of Fame Papers, 1947-1955 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - College Stadium Statistics, Undated (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - History of the NYU Football Team, 1967 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Football Team Notes and Roster, 1889 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Football Clipping, 1921 4 June (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - NYU Football Squads Personnel, 1928-1945 (Box 32, Folder 6)